<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark Cooper</title>
    <link>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mark Cooper</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reconciliation Engine</title>
      <link>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/projects/reconciliation-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/projects/reconciliation-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reconciliation-framework&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Reconciliation Framework&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#reconciliation-framework&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Reconciliation Engine is a modular batch-processing framework designed to execute named reconciliation routines with&#xA;precision and operational clarity. Built in Java and powered by Spring’s XML-based context configuration, the engine&#xA;allows for dynamic resolution of reconciliation logic at runtime using a provider pattern. This design enables flexible&#xA;orchestration of reconciliation workflows without requiring changes to the core application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At its heart, the engine accepts a reconciliation name as a command-line argument and uses a&#xA;&lt;code&gt;Provider&amp;lt;String, ReconcileEngine&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to locate the appropriate implementation. This approach decouples the execution&#xA;logic from the entry point, allowing new reconciliation types to be added simply by registering them in the Spring&#xA;context. Additional arguments passed at runtime can be used to inject system properties, making the engine highly&#xA;configurable and environment-aware.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Service Framework</title>
      <link>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/projects/service-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/projects/service-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.azure.com/mdcoopermc/_git/services-framework&#34;  class=&#34;external-link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;📥 browse this repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;service-framework&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Service Framework&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#service-framework&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Service Framework enables the development of &lt;strong&gt;event-based services&lt;/strong&gt; to orchestrate BAU workflows. It provides a&#xA;declarative, annotation-driven model for defining service behavior, routing logic, and execution conditions — all within&#xA;a Spring Boot environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;configuration-overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Configuration Overview&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#configuration-overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To activate default components like &lt;code&gt;RestTemplate&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ObjectMapper&lt;/code&gt;, launch your application with:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI / ML Systems</title>
      <link>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/about/aiml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/about/aiml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page documents my work in &lt;strong&gt;AI architecture&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;deep learning&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;reinforcement learning&lt;/strong&gt; — with a focus on&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;reproducibility&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;behavioural signal extraction&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;agentic orchestration&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I build systems that treat AI as a composable extension of infrastructure — not just a model, but a runtime framework&#xA;for &lt;strong&gt;insight&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;control&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;strategic reuse&lt;/strong&gt;. My platforms span &lt;strong&gt;character-level neural networks&lt;/strong&gt;, *&#xA;&lt;em&gt;transformer-based pipelines&lt;/em&gt;*, and &lt;strong&gt;OpenAI Gym–driven agents&lt;/strong&gt; — engineered for &lt;strong&gt;clarity&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;modularity&lt;/strong&gt;, and *&#xA;&lt;em&gt;embedded governance&lt;/em&gt;*.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Technology</title>
      <link>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/about/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/about/cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;cloud-technology&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Cloud Technology&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#cloud-technology&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section documents my work in cloud-native architecture, infrastructure-as-code, and serverless orchestration — with&#xA;a focus on reproducibility, runtime clarity, and strategic reuse across AWS and Azure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I build systems that treat cloud infrastructure as programmable, observable, and modular — engineered for fault&#xA;tolerance, secure delivery, and operational transparency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-aws--azure-architecture&#34;&gt;&#xA;  ☁️ AWS &amp;amp; Azure Architecture&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#-aws--azure-architecture&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve designed and delivered cloud-native platforms across both AWS and Azure, including:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finance Skills</title>
      <link>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/about/finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/about/finance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I design and deliver financial systems that support the full trade lifecycle — from capture and enrichment to&#xA;reconciliation, reporting, and compliance. My platforms are built for runtime clarity, auditability, and strategic reuse&#xA;across asset classes and regulatory regimes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve engineered solutions for FX/MM, derivatives, fixed income, and structured products, integrating standards like FIX,&#xA;FpML, and SWIFT MT/MX. My work spans real-time trade processing, exposure tracking, margining, and capital allocation —&#xA;with embedded controls for cost variance, earned value, and budget performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/projects/image-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/projects/image-classification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project was built to bring order to large, mixed‑quality media collections — the kind that blend treasured photos with everyday clutter. It takes a simple list of files and transforms it into a rich, structured dataset that’s easy to search, filter, and work with.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The process starts by checking what’s already known about each file and filling in any missing details. It then creates lightweight, high‑quality thumbnails to speed up processing and reduce strain on storage and networks. These thumbnails are cached so they can be reused without repeatedly loading the original files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Murex Engineering</title>
      <link>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/about/murex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/about/murex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve led &lt;strong&gt;Murex Trading engineering&lt;/strong&gt; across Société Générale, Rabobank, Daiwa, LSEG, and the London Stock Exchange — modernising trade feeds, upgrading environments, and embedding secure authentication and reporting into high‑volume trading infrastructure. My work spans FX/MM, derivatives, and fixed income workflows, with deep integration across pre‑trade, post‑trade, and risk domains. Whether orchestrating FIX, SWIFT, and FpML flows into MxMLExchange or refactoring Datamart pipelines, I treat Murex as a strategic substrate for runtime clarity, compliance, and operational control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real‑Time Orchestration Platform</title>
      <link>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/platforms/real-time-orchestration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/platforms/real-time-orchestration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Overview&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This platform was designed to unify complex, multi‑stage workflows into a single, scalable system capable of handling real‑time processing in a high‑stakes environment. It brings together service orchestration, data processing, and intelligent automation under one architecture, enabling teams to deliver faster, more reliably, and with greater flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;architecture--core-engineering&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Architecture &amp;amp; Core Engineering&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#architecture--core-engineering&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The build began with a modular architecture, where each service and calculation engine could be deployed independently yet work seamlessly together. This separation allowed for rapid iteration, reduced interdependencies, and consistent quality across all components. Automated CI/CD pipelines ensured that every change — from small configuration updates to major feature releases — could be deployed safely across development, testing, and production environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Skills</title>
      <link>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/about/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mdcooper-mc.github.io/about/software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I specialise in designing and delivering modular, high-performance systems across microservices architectures. With over&#xA;two decades of experience in capital markets, I’ve built platforms that span trading, risk, and regulatory domains —&#xA;engineered for resilience, observability, and strategic reuse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My core development expertise includes &lt;strong&gt;Java (8–21)&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spring Boot&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;GoLang&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Groovy&lt;/strong&gt; —&#xA;applied across microservices, event-driven systems, and secure API ecosystems. I’ve led the design of scalable backend&#xA;services, containerised deployments, and orchestration frameworks that support real-time trade processing and analytics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
